<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <pubdate>20220506</pubdate>
                <pubtime>114005</pubtime>
                <title>Fireshed Registry: Fireshed (Feature Layer)</title>
                <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                <pubinfo>
                    <publish>Forest Service Research Data Archive</publish>
                </pubinfo>
                <onlink>https://apps.fs.usda.gov/arcx/rest/services/EDW/EDW_FireshedRegistry_01/MapServer/0</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>The Fireshed Registry is a geospatial dashboard and decision tool built to organize information about wildfire transmission to communities and monitor progress towards risk reduction for communities from management investments. The concept behind the Fireshed Registry is to identify and map the source of risk rather than what is at risk across all lands in the conterminous United States. While the Fireshed Registry was organized around mapping the source of fire risk to communities, the framework does not preclude the assessment of other resource management priorities and trends such as water, fish and aquatic or wildlife habitat, or recreation. The Fireshed Registry is also a multi-scale decision tool for quantifying, prioritizing, and geospatially displaying wildfire transmission to buildings in adjacent or nearby communities. Fireshed areas in the Fireshed Registry are approximately 250,000 acre accounting units that are delineated based on a smoothed building exposure map of the conterminous United States. These boundaries were created by dividing up the landscape into regular-sized units that represent similar source levels of community exposure to wildfire risk. Project areas are approximately 25,000 acre accounting units nested within firesheds. This data publication includes a geodatabase that contains for both fireshed and project areas: boundaries, size, total annual number of buildings inside and outside of the area exposed by wildfires ignited within the area (based on 2010 housing unit data and 2014 fuels conditions), and percent of the area that has been disturbed since 2014 (2015-2018).Metadata and Downloads</abstract>
            <purpose>The fireshed and project area boundaries are designed to delineate hotspots of fire transmission to adjacent or nearby communities to facilitate cohesive cross-boundary risk mitigation planning. Exposure metrics are designed to be used for strategic allocation. Tactical operations should incorporate additional local knowledge.</purpose>
            <supplinf>This data publication was originally published on 10/27/2020. On 10/20/2021 minor metadata updates were made to correct an author's name. Additionally, a previous fireshed name change that accidentally wasn't carried over to the project areasa layer has been corrected. On 01/18/2022, an updated version of the geodatabase was released. This update incorporated newer fireshed names and related fireshed codes. No boundaries were changed.</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <rngdates>
                    <begdate>20140101</begdate>
                    <enddate>20220524</enddate>
                </rngdates>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>Ground condition</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
            <update>Irregular</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-127.881563</westbc>
                <eastbc>-65.329158</eastbc>
                <northbc>51.595025</northbc>
                <southbc>22.932504</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
                <themekey>geospatial</themekey>
                <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
                <themekey>wildfire management</themekey>
                <themekey>wildfire exposure</themekey>
                <themekey>wildfire transmission</themekey>
                <themekey>wildfire</themekey>
                <themekey>Fire effects on environment</themekey>
                <themekey>Forest management</themekey>
                <themekey>Wildland/urban interface</themekey>
                <themekey>Natural Resource Management &amp; Use</themekey>
                <themekey>Fire</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>None</placekt>
                <placekey>United States</placekey>
            </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>Other Constraints</accconst>
        <useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>USDA Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station</cntorg>
                    <cntper>Michelle Day</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>Biological Scientist</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>3200 SW Jefferson Way</address>
                    <city>Corvallis</city>
                    <state>OR</state>
                    <postal>97331</postal>
                    <country>UNITED STATES</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>541-758-7758</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>michelle.day@usda.gov</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>This project was funded by the USDA Forest Service, State &amp; Private Forestry and the USDA Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. Additional acknowledgments are extended to Portland State University, Oregon State University, USDA Forest Service International Visitor Program, and Kingbird Software.</datacred>
        <native>Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.7.1.11595</native>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>The fuels data used in this prediction are not current, due to the data vintage of fuel conditions used in the available FSim simulations. Thus our predictions in areas that have had disturbance and management since 2014 should be used with caution, with consideration of finer scaled data. As with all risk products there is substantial uncertainty associated with these estimates. This assessment concerns exposure and not risk as we make no predictions about loss. The boundaries among adjacent firesheds are the product of the “Simple Linear Iterative Clustering” (SLIC) algorithm, which is dependent on the initial placement of points from which the image segments (i.e., clusters) are derived. This means that the boundaries between adjacent firesheds, particularly those in areas with homogenous exposure, may vary over successive runs. These data represent one such solution. Achanta, R.; Shaji, A.; Smith, K.; Lucchi, A.; Fua, P.; Süsstrunk, S. 2012. SLIC superpixels compared to state-of-the-art superpixel methods. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence 34(11): 2274-2282. https://doi.org/10.1109/tpami.2012.120</attraccr>
            <qattracc>
                <attracce>See Method Description</attracce>
            </qattracc>
        </attracc>
        <logic>No consistency evaluation was performed.</logic>
        <complete>Fireshed and project area boundaries reflect the resolution of the underlying building exposure raster of 270 meters. These boundaries can be considered complete, but note that boundaries representing features such as national boundaries and coastlines will be greatly generalized and, in the case of islands, they may be omitted entirely.</complete>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20220506</pubdate>
                        <title>California Wildfire Perimeters, (1950+)</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20150101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20180101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>Publication Date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>California Wildfire Perimeters, (1950+)</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Vector spatial wildfire and prescribed burning data for the years 2015-2018.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20220506</pubdate>
                        <title>Monitoring Trends in Burn Severity (MTBS)</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20150101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20180101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>Publication Date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Monitoring Trends in Burn Severity (MTBS)</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Vector special wildfire perimeter data were obtained for the years 2015-2018.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20220506</pubdate>
                        <title>Census Block Level Housing Change 1990 - 2010 for the Conterminous United States</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20100101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>Publication Date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Census Block Level Housing Change 1990 - 2010 for the Conterminous United States</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Mapped housing and population counts from the 2010 U.S. Census data at the block group level.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20220506</pubdate>
                        <pubtime>114005</pubtime>
                        <title>Forest Service Activity Tracking System (FACTS)</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20150101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20180101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>Publication Date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Forest Service Activity Tracking System (FACTS)</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Records of prescribed fire and mechanical fuels treatment data.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20220506</pubdate>
                        <pubtime>114005</pubtime>
                        <title>LANDFIRE Public Events Geodatabase</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20150101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20180101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>Publication Date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>LANDFIRE Public Events Geodatabase</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Vector spatial data for the years 2015-2018 for wildfire perimeters and for various forest management activities, including prescribed burning, canopy thinning, and mastication.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>To account for the fact that wildfire risk and risk mitigation efforts occur at multiple scales, we assessed risk exposure at stand-, project-, and fireshed-level scales. We created these layers in such a way that a finer-scale is nested within a coarser-scale, in much the same way as a drainage is nested within a larger watershed. This dataset includes the project- and fireshed-scale boundaries, together with estimates of the annual number of buildings exposed from ignitions within these boundaries.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20191114</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>“Firesheds” and "Project Areas" within the Fireshed Registry are nested accounting units that are delineated based on a smoothed building exposure map of the conterminous U.S. These boundaries were created by dividing up the landscape into comparably-sized units that represent similar source levels of community exposure to wildfire risk. The size of firesheds was specified to contain 99% of the large fires, with fire sizes generally smaller than 250,000 acres, although the largest extreme event fires can span multiple firesheds.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20191114</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>The exposure grid was divided into roughly equal-sized spatial units at two different scales: the project area (~25,000 acres) and the fireshed (~250,000 acres). Both units were defined using image segmentation (SLIC) based on both geographic distance and magnitude of exposure. The approach is based on a modified form of K-means clustering that includes an additional parameter to account for the cluster shape. In order to ensure the units of both scales were nested, we adjusted the boundary of the fireshed to match underlying project areas boundaries using a majority rule. Thus, when a project area spanned two firesheds, the overlapping area was added to the majority fireshed (and subtracted from the minority fireshed).</procdesc>
                <procdate>20191114</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Building exposure for the entire U.S. was first calculated using FSim ignition points and fire perimeters (using a range of historical fire weather and fuels data from LANDFIRE 2014) and intersecting perimeters with SILVIS wildland urban interface polygons (ca. 2010) (Radeloff et al. 2005, SILVIS Lab 2012) and attributing annual exposure to those ignitions. This means that values reflect the source of exposure, as opposed to where buildings are actually located. Radeloff, V. C.; Hammer, R. B.; Stewart, S. I.; Fried, J. S.; Holcomb, S. S.; McKeefry, J. F. 2005. The wildland-urban interface in the United States. Ecological Applications 15:799-805.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20191114</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Exposure values were aggregated by projecting points onto a 270-m grid. To emphasize the general geographic patterns of risk and account for the stochasticity of extreme fire events, the exposure grid was first log10-transformed and then smoothed using focal statistics using a moving circular window with a 10-kilometer (km) radius using the focal function in the R Raster package. The entire grid was then normalized (0-1). Hijmans, Robert J.; van Etten, Jacob. 2012. raster: Geographic analysis and modeling with raster data. R package version 2.0-12. http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=raster</procdesc>
                <procdate>20191114</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Pixel values from the original 270-m grid (i.e., prior to being log10-transformed and smoothed) were summed to estimate exposure at the project- and fireshed-levels. Note that since simulated fires from Fsim were modeled based on 2014 fuels, the exposure summaries here do not include exposure from stands that have been disturbed by wildfire or management activities since 2014. Records of prescribed fire and mechanical fuels treatment data from the USDA Forest Service Activity Tracking System (FACTS 2020), wildfire area burned data from MTBS (2020), and prescribed fire data from CalFire (2020) nor present in FACTS or MTBS were used to adjust exposure with the assumption that areas recently treated (2015-2018) or burned would not contribute to wildfire exposure to communities.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20200831</procdate>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>Complete chain</sdtstype>
                <ptvctcnt>7688</ptvctcnt>
            </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
    </spdoinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>S_USA.Fire_FireshedReg_Fireshed</enttypl>
                <enttypd>Vector polygons: “Firesheds” within the Fireshed Registry are approximately 250,000 acre accounting units that are delineated based on a smoothed building exposure map of the conterminous United States. These boundaries were created by dividing up the landscape into regular-sized units that represent similar source levels of community exposure to wildfire risk.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>None</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Fireshed_Name</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Fireshed name; fireshed names were using a hierarchy of U.S. Census populated place names based on the highest population place within the fireshed, and for fireshed without populated places, names were assigned using the Geographic Names Information System; in rare cases names were manually assigned.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Free text</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Area_HA</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Fireshed area, in hectares</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Any value &gt; 0</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>NoPAs</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Number of project areas that fall within the fireshed boundary [4-24]</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <rdom>
                                                						
                        
                        <rdommin>4</rdommin>
                                                						
                        
                        <rdommax>24</rdommax>
                                                					
                    
                    </rdom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>ESRI defined shape area (field added by default)</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>ESRI software automatically generated area for the shape</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Fireshed_State</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>State that the majority of fireshed falls within.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>State abbreviation (lower 48 or District of Columbia)</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Fireshed_ID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Unique Fireshed ID.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <rdom>
                                                						
                        
                        <rdommin>1</rdommin>
                                                						
                        
                        <rdommax>7709</rdommax>
                                                					
                    
                    </rdom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>ESRI defined shape length (field added by default)</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>ESRI software automatically generated length for the shape</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Fireshed_Code</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Fireshed codes are abbreviated versions of the fireshed name</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Free text</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Regional_All_Land_Rank</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>For each FS Region, rank all firesheds from highest to lowest by the sum of Exp_USFS_ManagedForest plus Exp_NonUSFS_ManagedForest.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Integer positive values.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_USFS_Managed</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from US Forest Service lands available for mechanical treatment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_USFS filtered to only inlcude manageable lands. Filter based on the protected areas database (USGS, 2016, 2019) plus USFS wilderness, roadless and nationally designated areas databases. Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_USFS_Protected should equal Exp_USFS. Managed exposure includes both forested and non-forested exposure.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Regional_USFS_Rank</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>For each FS Region, rank all firesheds from highest to lowest by Exp_USFS_ManagedForest values.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Integer positive values.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_USFS_ManagedConifer</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from US Forest Service lands with conifer land cover available for mechanical treatment; not available for eastern US.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_USFS filtered for both conifer lands and manageable landbase. Internal validation: This field should be a less than or equal to both Exp_USFS_Conifer and Exp_USFS_Managed.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_USFS_ManagedForest</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from US Forest Service lands with forested land cover available for mechanical treatment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_USFS filtered to for both forested lands and manageable landbase. Internal validation: This field should be less than or equal to both Exp_USFS_Managed and Exp_USFS_Forest.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Start_Date</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Time series data management. The beginning date when this row of data was accurate.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI Date - Time field type, with Dates only.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Calendar dates.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>National_All_Land_Rank</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Rank all firesheds from highest to lowest based on the sum of Exp_USFS_ManagedForest and Exp_NonUSFS_ManagedForest values.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Integer positive values.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_USFS_Protected</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from US Forest Service lands not available for mechanical treatment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_USFS filtered to only inlcude protected lands. Filter based on the protected areas database (USGS, 2016, 2019) plus USFS wilderness, roadless and nationally designated areas databases. Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_USFS_Managed should equal Exp_USFS.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from non-Forest Service lands.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_Total filtered to exclude Forest Service lands. Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_FS should equal Exp_Total. Compare NonFS exposure to USFS exposure to understand how NonFS lands contribute to the overall exposure.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_USFS_Conifer</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from US Forest Service lands with conifer land cover.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_USFS filtered to only inlcude conifer lands. Filter based on Forest Vegetation Simulator forest types (Crookston and Dixon, 2005). Internal validation: This field should be a less than or equal to Exp_USFS_Forest. Conifer exposure is from both managed and protected lands.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_USFS_NonForest</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from US Forest Service lands without forested land cover.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_USFS filtered to only inlcude non-forested lands. Filter based on the National Landcover Data (USGS, 2011). Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_USFS_Forest should equal Exp_USFS. Non-forested exposure is from both managed and protected lands.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS_Forest</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from non-Forest Service lands with forested land cover.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Double</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS_ManagedConifer</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from non-Forest Service lands with conifer land cover available for mechanical treatment; not available for eastern US.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_USFS filtered for both conifer lands and manageable landbase. Internal validation: This field should be a less than or equal to both Exp_USFS_Conifer and Exp_USFS_Managed. This exposure measure (with 2019-2020 disturbance) was used to model action in "Planning for future fire: Scenario analysis of an accelerated fuel reduction plan for the western United States", https://www.fs.usda.gov/treesearch/pubs/63129.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_USFS_Forest</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from US Forest Service lands with forested land cover.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_USFS filtered to only inlcude forested lands. Filter based on the National Landcover Data (USGS, 2011). Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_USFS_NonForest should equal Exp_USFS. Forested exposure is from both managed and protected lands.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Crisis_Strategy</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Firesheds used in the FY 2022 Landscape analysis process.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>'All-Lands' priority firesheds were published with the "Confronting the Wildfire Crisis" strategy document that was released in December of 2021. The document included a map of 141 firesheds where scenario planning scheduled the most treatment throughout the western U.S. https://usdagcc.sharepoint.com/sites/fs-wo-oc/Fire-Hub/SiteAssets/Confronting%20the%20Wildfire%20Crisis/Confronting%20the%20Wildfire%20Crisis.pdf 'USFS-Only' priority firesheds include an additional list of 130 firesheds with the highest measure of manageable conifer exposure on Forest Service lands. Where both criteria are met, only the 'All-Lands' label is applied.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>'All-Lands', 'USFS-Only', or null</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Dist_Vs</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>All exposure metrics are updated for disturbance as defined here.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Years of disturbance activities in the value domain are defined as Dist_Vs = 2019-2020 accounts for hazardous fuels treatments through 2019 and wildfire disturbances through October 2020; Dist_Vs = 2021 accounts for disturbances through 2021. More values will be added for future updates.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>'2019-2020', '2021'</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS_ManagedForest</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from non-Forest Service lands with forested land cover available for mechanical treatment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_NonFS filtered for both forested lands and manageable landbase. Internal validation: This field should be less than or equal to both Exp_NonFS_Managed and Exp_NonFS_Forest.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS_NonForest</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from non-Forest Service lands without forested land cover.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_NonFS filtered to only inlcude non-forested lands. Filter based on the National Landcover Data (USGS, 2011). Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_NonFS_Prot should equal Exp_NonFS. Non-forested exposure is from both managed and protected lands.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS_Conifer</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from non-Forest Service lands with conifer land cover.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_NonFS filtered to only inlcude conifer lands. Filter based on Forest Vegetation Simulator forest types (Crookston and Dixon, 2005). Internal validation: This field should be less than or equal to Exp_NonFS_Forest. Conifer exposure is from both managed and protected lands.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS_Managed</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from non-Forest Service lands available for mechanical treatment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_NonFS filtered to only inlcude manageable lands. Filter based on the protected areas database (USGS, 2016, 2019) plus USFS wilderness, roadless and nationally designated areas databases. Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_NonFS_Protected should equal Exp_NonFS. Managed exposure includes both forested and non-forested exposure.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS_Protected</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from non-Forest Service lands not available for mechanical treatment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_NonFS filtered to only inlcude protected lands. Filter based on the protected areas database (USGS, 2016, 2019) plus USFS wilderness, roadless and nationally designated areas databases. Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_NonFS_Managed should equal Exp_NonFS.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>KEY_PERFORMANCE_INDICATOR</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Is work in the fireshed contributing to the fireshed key performance indicator?</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>FAM will determine which firesheds are included in the KPI measurement.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>Yes</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Yes</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>USFS</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>"Yes" or "No"</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>No</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>No</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>USFS</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>National_USFS_Rank</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Rank all firesheds from highest to lowest by Exp_USFS_ManagedForest values.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Integer positive values.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>End_Date</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Time series data management. The ending date when this row of data was accurate. Null values indicate that the record is currently accurate.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI Date - Time field type, with Dates only.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Calendar dates.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_USFS</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure from US Forest Service lands.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_Total filtered to only inlcude US Forest Service ownwership. Internal validation: This field combined with Exp_NonFS should equal Exp_Total. Compare USFS exposure to NonFS exposure to understand how USFS lands contribute to the overall exposure.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_NonFS_NonConifer_HiHaz</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Predicted building exposure excluding non-Forest Service lands, excluding conifer land cover, filtered for high or very high hazard potential, and available for mechanical treatment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Attribute Exp_NonFS_Managed filtered to exclude conifer land cover and moderate or low hazard potential. Wildfire hazard potential filter based on (Dillon and Gilbertson-Day, 2020); not available for eastern US. This exposure measure was explicitly used in the 2021 3-zone scenario for the western US, shared through the "Confronting the Wildfire Crisis Strategy."</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Exp_Total</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Total predicted building exposure from ignitions on undisturbed lands within this fireshed. Exp_Total describes the overall exposure of structures to wildfire.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Bunzel et.al.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Decimal positive values including zero and null.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FSHED_ID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Unique fireshed identifier</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <rdom>
                                                						
                        
                        <rdommin>1</rdommin>
                                                						
                        
                        <rdommax>7709</rdommax>
                                                					
                    
                    </rdom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
        <overview>
            <eaover>This dataset is a combination of the S_USA.Fire_FireshedReg_Fireshed feature class and the related S_USA.Fire_FireshedReg_Fireshed_Exp table in the Production version of the EDW SDE geodatabase. Fireshed boundaries in this data set are accounting units that facilitate tracking and prioritizing fireshed exposure risk. They are nested boundaries delineating wildfire transmission to communities for monitoring progress towards risk reduction from management investments. They do not follow identifiable geographic features. The attributes in this online version of this dataset capture multiple measures from fireshed registry structure exposure datasets generated by researchers for the eastern and western conterminous United States. 

Fireshed science is a way to measure the relative likelihood that a fire in this area will grow and encompass structures. These fireshed registry structure exposure measures include multiple years of results, presented with Start and End dates to support temporal system versioning. Null values in the exposure attributes occur when no calculation was done. This may happen if the selected land base (such as USFS ownership) does not occur in the selected spatial area. Null is also used when an attribute is only calculated for part of the U.S. Researchers originally called these "annual TRansmission" (a.k.a. 'aTR') values. Those labels were changed to Esposure values, 'Exp' for simpler shorthand label.</eaover>
            <eadetcit>None provided</eadetcit>
        </overview>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <distrib>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>physical</addrtype>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20250</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <resdesc>RDS-2020-0054</resdesc>
        <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>GDB</formname>
                    <formvern>see Format Specification</formvern>
                    <formspec>ArcGIS Geodatabase File</formspec>
                    <filedec>Files zipped with 7-Zip 19.0</filedec>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://doi.org/10.2737/RDS-2020-0054</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                        <accinstr>RDS-2020-0054</accinstr>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
        </stdorder>
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20220608</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>USDA Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station</cntorg>
                    <cntper>Michelle Day</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>Biological Scientist</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>3200 SW Jefferson Way</address>
                    <city>Corvallis</city>
                    <state>OR</state>
                    <postal>97331</postal>
                    <country>UNITED STATES</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>541-758-7758</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>michelle.day@usda.gov</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
